So far you have learned some tricks to implement
これまで パーティクルフィルターを実装するためのいくつかのテクニックと
the particle filter and how to assess
フィルターの正確さを 評価する方法を学んだ
the accuracy of your filter.
ことになります
Now I'll give you an overview of the code
ここで コードの概要を説明します
that you'll be using to complete your project.
このコードは プロジェクトを完成させる ために使用します
Let's first look at the file main.cvp.
最初に maincpp ファイルを見てみましょう
This file will run your particle filter
このファイルは粒子フィルター を実行するだけでなく
as well as measure its runtime and calculate
実行時間を測定して 各ステップにおいて
the weighted error at each time step.
加重誤差 を計算します
The first thing you'll need to do
最初に しなければならない点は
is set the number of particles in your filter
To Do コメントにおいてフィルター内の 粒子の数
under this To Do comment.
を設定することです
M is the number of particles to draw.
M は 抽出する粒子の 数です
Here I have set the uncertainties
これは 使用することになる 異なる測定の
for the different measurements that you'll be using.
不確実性 です
Next the main function reads in the math data, the control
次に 各タイム ステップで メイン関数が 数学データ 制御データ
data, and the observation data for each time step.
観察データ を読み取ります
In this for loop, you'll implement
このループでは To Do コメントにおいて
one step of your particle filter under this To Do comment here.
粒子フィルターの 1 ステップ を実装することができます
At the end of each time step, you
各時間のステップにおいて 加重エラー
will calculate and print out the weighted error.
を計算し 表示します
Finally, after your particle filter
最後に 粒子フィルター
has gone through the entire driving sequence,
が すべての運転シーケンスを終了すると
the main function will calculate the runtime for your filter,
メイン関数は フィルターの実行時間を計算し
and that's it for main.cvp.
maincpp となります
You will implement most of the particle filter code
多くの 粒子フィルター コードを
in particlefilter.cvp.
particlefilter.cpp で実装します
This file contains all of the implementations
このファイルには 粒子フィルター クラス
of the functions of the particle filter class.
の関数の実装が 含まれます
Now we'll go over each function you'll
プロジェクトを完了するために 各関数を
have to complete to finish the project.
振り返ります
The first function you'll have to complete is init.
最初に完了すべき関数は init です
This function takes as input a GPS position,
この関数は 測定に関する GPS 位置の入力
an initial heading estimate, and an array of uncertainties
初期方位推定値 一連の不確実性
for these measurements.
を取ります
It then should sample from a Gaussion distribution centered
これらの測定値を中心とした ガウス分布
around these measurements to initialize all the particles.
からサンプリングして すべての粒子を初期化します
It should also initialize all particle weights to 1.
また すべての粒子の重量を 1 に初期化します
You can look at the details for the particle_struct
ここで particle_struct
and particle_filter.h.
の詳細は、particle_filterhで確認できます
The particle filter class has an internal structure
粒子フィルター クラス には 更新されている
of particles that is updated.
粒子の内部構造があります
So nothing is returned from this function.
この関数からは 何も返されません
The next function is prediction.
次の関数は 予測です
This function takes as input the amount
この関数は 入力として
of time between time steps, the velocity and yaw rate
時間ステップ間の時間量 速度とヨー レート
measurement uncertainties, and the current time step velocity
測定の不確実性 現在のタイムステップ速度
and yaw rate measurements.
ヨー レート測定を取ります
Using these measurements, it should
これらの測定値を 用いて
update each particle's position estimates
各パーティクルの 予測位置を更新し
and account for sensor noise by adding Gaussian noise.
ガウス ノイズを追加することで センサー ノイズ を計算します
Once again, you can add Gaussian noise
繰り返しになりますが 更新されたパーティクル位置
by sampling from a Gaussion distribution
に等しい平均値と 測定値の標準偏差に等しい
with mean equal to the updated particle position,
標準偏差をもつ ガウス分布から
and standard deviation equal to the standard deviation
サンプリングすることによって ガウス ノイズ
of the measurements.
を追加できます
The data association function here
データ関連 関数
takes as input two vectors of landmark obs objects.
は入力としてランドマーク obs オブジェクトの 2 つのベクトルを取ります
You can find the definition for this struct
helperfunctions.h. では この構造の
in helperfunctions.h.
定義を見つけることができます
This first vector is the prediction measurements
この最初のベクトルは 一つの粒子とセンサー範囲内の地図の
between one particular particle and all of the map
ランドマークとの間の 予測測定
landmarks within sensor range.
です
This other vector here is the actual landmark measurements
他のベクトルは LIDAR から収集された
gathered from the LIDAR.
実際のランドマークの測定値です
This function will perform nearest neighbor data
この関数は 最も近いデータの
association and assign each sensor observation
関連付けを行い 各センサーの観察データ
the map landmark ID associated with it.
を関連している地図のランドマークに割り当て ます
Next you'll need to complete the update weights function.
次に 重み更新関数を 完了する必要があります
This function takes the range of the sensor,
この関数は 入力として
the landmark measurement uncertainties,
センサーの範囲 ランドマークの測定の不確実性
a vector of landmark measurements,
ランドマーク測定 のベクトル
and the map landmarks as input.
地図のランドマークを取ります
The first thing you'll need to do here
ここですべき 最初のことは
is to predict measurements to all the map
各パーティクルの センサー範囲内の測定を
landmarks within sensor range for each particle.
全てのマップ上にあるランドマークに 対する測定値を予測することです
Once you have these predicted landmark measurements,
この ランドマーク測定を予測している場合は 実装した
you can use the data association function
データ関連付け 関数
you've implemented to associate the sensor measurements to map
により センサー測定を
landmarks.
地図のランドマークに関連付けることができます
You'll need these associations to calculate
多変量ガウス分布 確率密度関数
the new weight of each particle by using
を使用して 各パーティクルの新しい重み
the multivariate Gaussian probability density function
を計算するために 関連が必要ですが
we discussed in the lesson.
このレッスンで説明します
Finally, you'll have to normalize these weights so
最後に 重みが
that they'll be in the range 0 to 1
0 ～ 1 の範囲になるように正規化します
because next you'll use these weights as probabilities
その理由としては これらの重みをリサンプリングの
for resampling.
確率として使用するからです
You're almost there.
完成まであと一歩です
The next function is the resample function.
次の関数は リサンプル関数です
You can use the weights of the particles in your particle
粒子の重みを 粒子
filter and c++ standard libraries discrete distribution
フィルターで使用し c++ 標準の ライブラリ離散分布
function to update your particles to the Bayesian
関数 の重みを使用して ベイズの
posterior distribution.
事後分布に更新します
Finally, you're at the last step.
最後の ステップです
You'll evaluate your particle filter
加重誤差を計算して 粒子フィルター
by calculating the weighted error.
を 評価できます
This function takes the ground truth position
この関数は入力として 特定の時間ステップにおいて
at a particular time step as input
地上検証データ 位置を取り
and calculates the weighted error of your particle filter
各粒子の重み を使って粒子フィルター
using the weights of each particle.
の加重 エラーを計算します
Feel free to check out the files helperfunction.h,
コードの詳細に興味がある場合は helperfunction.h
map.h, and particlefilter.h if you're curious about the finer
map.h particlefilter.h if ファイルを確認
details of the code.
するようにします
To build and run your code, open a terminal
コードをビルドして 実行するには 端末を開き
and simply go to the localization particle filter
ローカライゼーション粒子フィルター
home directory, then type build.sh
のホーム ディレクトリを開き build.sh
and then run.sh to run your particle filter.
を入力し 粒子フィルターを実行するために .sh を実行します
Now I'm handing it over to you.
皆さんに引き継ぎます
You have all the tools you'll need to complete the particle
粒子フィルターのプロジェクトを完成させるのに 必要なツールは
filter project.
すべてそろっています
Have fun and see you on the other side.
楽しんでください 別のレッスンでお会いしましょう